# Amitesh Shukla

Noida, UP | 9540214483 shukla.amitesh23@gmail.com

# Synopsis

Talented software development professional (full stack developer) with experience of 4 years 6 months in applications. Consistent in delivering clean, error-free, reliable code to meet current or expected needs. Well-versed in software trends and confident in multiple languages, frameworks and programming tools.

### Technical Acquaintance

Java 8, springboot, Oracle DB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, JavaScript, AngularJS, Hibernate, JPA, Maven, Gradle, Junit, Mockito, Git, GitHub, AWS, Docker, Jenkins, Microservices, Rest Api, Hystrix, Mongo DB, Swagger, Github, STS, Eclipse, Postman, Amazon S3, Amazon Lambda, CSS, Bootstrap, JQuery, Apache Tomcat Server, AWS codecommit, RabbitMQ, Putty

### Work Experience

Cognizant Technology Solutions | UP, Noida Software Engineer | 11/2021 – Present Bayer C- Commercial Advisor P | Sofware Engineer- 1yr 8 months(Nov 2021- Jun 2023):

Project Description: Mobile and Web application used to order the Bayer Product by advisor on behalf of farmers across APAC and Africa region and managing the commission for Advisors.

## Roles and Responsibilities:

Developed testable software using agile methodologies to create high-quality deliverables

Contributed to sprint planning, prioritising backlogs to meet new demands.

Integrated third-party applications into existing software, enhancing features and performance.

Aligned projects with requirements and specifications to deliver above-benchmark results.

TIC Retail Services India Pvt Ltd. | Haryana, Gurugram Software Engineer | 11/2019 - 10/2021 Re-warehoouse System | Software Engineer - (Aug 2020 - Oct 2021)

Project Description: Application is developing to provide all warehouse processes like put away items, move items, pick orders, dispatch orders etc.

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

Part of development team as java full stack developer which involved end to end application development and test along with deployment support.

Contributed to sprint planning, prioritising backlogs to meet new demands.

Integrated third-party applications into existing software, enhancing features and performance.

Argo Application | Software Engineer - (May 2020 - July 2021)

Project Description: This application was developed to provide logistic supports to retailers. It looked after managing the seller's details and their inventories. It helped to create hierarchical structures of the items for quick dispatch and audit.

# Roles and Responsibilities:

Part of development team as java full stack developer which involved end to end application development and test along with deployment support.

Contributed to sprint planning, prioritising backlogs to meet new demands.

Integrated third-party applications into existing software, enhancing features and performance.

ESB Application | Java Developer - (Nov 2019 - Apr 2020)

Project Description: ESB application is a middleware application. It is used to distribute work among connected components of an application.

#### Roles and Responsibilities:

Being a java full stack developer, I worked on integration of rest apis in ESB.

Part of development team as java full stack developer which involved end to end application development and test along with deployment support.

Contributed to sprint planning, prioritising backlogs to meet new demands.

Integrated third-party applications into existing software, enhancing features and performance.

CSC E-Governance India Limited | Delhi, New Delhi Java Developer | 11/2018 - 10/2019 JobCard Application(UCO Bank) | Java Developer (Nov 2018 - Oct 2019)

Project Description: This application provides the e-kyc of Uco bank customers coming for account opening in the bank.

# Roles and Responsibilities:

Worked on registration modules as a java full stack developer and part of development team which involved end to end application development and test along with deployment support.

Contributed to all phases of the development lifecycle, from design to writing and developing.

Analysed user requirements before starting Java development projects to understand application layout and design.

#### Education

SVM | Prayagraj, UP High School with 66%

RRDSVN | Prayagraj, UP Intermediate with 77.4%.

Shambhunath Institute of Technology | Prayagraj, UP Bachelor Of Technology with 69.4%

### Certificates

Java (SE 8) Certification, AWS Certification (In progress)

### Awards

Received star performer award from Re-Warehouse system team.

Got appreciation from a client (Centene USA) for contribution in a pilot project.